Huff-Hylton Families Papers, 1803-1816, 1858-1882, 1975, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Huff-Hylton Families Papers, 1803-1816, 1858-1882, 1975, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1998-001
1 box; 0.3 cu. ft.
The collection consists of items from the early 1800s pertaining to the business dealings of Samuel Huff of Montgomery (now Floyd) County, Virginia. Materials include promissory notes, fines for Huff's failure to attend muster of the 75th Regiment of the Virginia Militia, and an indenture for land.
Huff family, Floyd County, Va.; Hylton family, Floyd County, Va.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Huff-Hylton Families Papers were donated to Special Collections in May 1998. Additional materials were donated in July 1998.
Alternate Form Available
Transcriptions and images (jpgs) of several letters and other items in this collection are available. See the "Contents List" for links to images and transcripts.
Biographical Information
The Huff and Hylton families settled in what is now Floyd County, but prior to 1831 was Montgomery County, Virginia, in the late 1700s and early 1800s. The Huff family owned land on the west fork of the Little River.
Lorenzo Dow Hylton was born on August 16, 1830, son of Burwell Hylton [Hilton] and Mary Ann Slusher. On July 23, 1857, he married Barbara Ellen Huff (1828-1911). The 1860 Virginia census lists him as being a resident of Floyd County, age 29, his occupation as a machinist, worth $484.00. During the Civil War he enlisted in Company D of the 54th Virginia Infantry on March 24, 1862, in Abingdon, Virginia, as a 1st Lieutenant. He was wounded in action at Missionary Ridge, Tennessee, on November 25, 1863, and died in Marietta [Georgia] Hospital on February 13, 1864. He is buried in a Confederate cemetery in Marietta, Georgia. After Hylton's death his wife Barbara Ellen Huff Hylton married James Dillon [Dillion] and moved to Patrick County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of items from the early 1800s pertaining to the business dealings of Samuel Huff of Montgomery (now Floyd) County. Materials include promissory notes, fines for Huff's failure to attend muster of the 75th Regiment of the Virginia Militia, and an indenture for land.
The collection also consists of six letters written by Lorenzo Dow Hylton to his wife Barbara while he served in Company D of the 54th Virginia Infantry during the Civil War, and one letter to him from Barbara. Included in the collection are letters from Barbara's cousin, Samuel Slusher, and brother-in-law, Ira Hylton, about Lorenzo Hylton's death in a Confederate hospital in Marietta, Georgia, and letters from Martha Huff of Indiana, to Barbara.
Genealogical information about the Hylton family, compiled by a descendent of the family, is also a part of the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically. Undated materials are at the end of the collection.
Index Terms
Persons:
Huff, Samuel, Montgomery County, Va.; Hylton, Barbara Ellen Huff, 1828-1911; Hylton, Lorenzo Dow, 1830-1864
Subjects:
Civil War; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- Family papers, 1803-1816, 1858-1882, 1975, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Fine of 75 cents to Samuel Huff of Capt. Robertson's Company for failing to attend a muster on October 21, 1803, signed by E. Howard, October 29, 1803.
  - Promissory note from Thos. Goodson that he will pay George Melton two pounds Five shillings. Also signed by Sammuel Huff, October 23, 1803.
  - Promissory note from Bird Smith that he will give Samuel Huff 30 acres of land. Note also mentions George and John Hilton, February 4, 1805.
  - Letter from John Weddle of Montgomery County, Ohio, to Samuel Huff of Montgomery County, Virginia, August 1806.
    Transcription
    Page 1
    Page 2
  - Promissory note from James Keef to William Byon in the amount of eight dollars to be paid on or before November 1, 1806, September 23, 1806.
  - Indenture made between Bird and Rhoda Smith and William Thompson, for land on the West Fork of Little River in Montgomery County, Virginia, March 3, 1807.
  - Promissory note from Sam. Huff that he will pay John Snyder one pound and ninepence, January 12, 1808.
  - Promissory note from Samuel Huff that he will pay James Goad the sum of $10.00, October 8, 1808.
  - Promissory note from James Brawney to Samuel Huff for the sum of four dollars, four shillings, and two sixpence, February 23, 1812.
  - Fine of 1 dollar, 50 cents to Samuel Huff for delinquency at batallion and August muster, November 1812.
  - Fine of one dollar to Samuel Huff of the first Battalion of the 75th Regiment of the Virginia Militia, for failing to attend muster, October 30, 1813.
  - Fine of 75 cents to Samuel Huff of the first Battalion of the 75th Regiment of the Virginia Militia, for failing to attend muster, November 28, 1814.
  - Montgomery County loan account in the name of Samuel Huff, July 31, 1816.
  - Receipt from L.D. Hylton to George M. Slusher for sawing 581 feet of inch plank at forty cents per hundred, $2.32, January 8, 1858.
  - Letter from Barbara E. Hylton in Floyd County, Virginia, to her husband, L. D. Hylton, April 24, 1862.
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton at "Salt Vill Washington Co Va" to his wife Barbara Hylton, May 10, 1862.
  - From L.D. Hylton in Bath Co., Kentucky, to his wife, B.E. Hylton, October 18, 1862.
    Page 3
    Page 4
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton in "Camp near Pettersburg" to his wife, B.E. Hylton, December 28, 1862.
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton to Burwell Hylton, February 1, 1863.
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton in "Camp on Black Water Virginia" to his wife Barbara Hylton, March 12, 1863.
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton in "Marrieta, G.A." to B.E. Hylton, January 20, 1864.
  - Letter from Samuel Slusher in "Camp Near Dalton Ga," to his cousin Barbara E. Hylton, telling her about Lorenzo Hylton's death in Marietta, Georgia, February 15, 1864.
  - Five dollar Confederate Bond, February 17, 1864.
  - Letter from Ira S. Hylton in Dalton, Georgia, to Barbara E. Hylton, February 18, 1864.
  - Promissory note from Barbara E. Hylton to pay Riley H. Hylton the sum of $8.80, October 7, 1865.
  - Letter from Martha Huff in Hundrix County, Indiana, to sister Barbara Hylton, August 8, 1866.
  - Letter from Martha Huff in Hundrix County, Indiana, to sister Barbara Hylton and Mother Huff, October 24, 1866.
  - Letter from Martha Huff of Putnam County, Indiana to Barbara E. Hylton; on back of letter another letter from Martha Huff to James Huff, April 11, 1875.
  - Assignment of the real estate in Patrick County, Virginia, of James Dillion to his widow Barbara E. Dillion, signed by the Commissioners of the County Court of Patrick County, September 9, 1882.
  - Letter from Barbara M. Goscha, City Clerk of the City of Marietta, Georgia, to Robert Howell, about locating the grave of L.D. Hylton in the Confederate Cemetery, June 12, 1975.
  - Certificate from the Virginia State Library, certifying information about L.D. Hylton's Civil War record, July 2, 1975.
  - Empty envelope addressed to Mrs. Barbara E. Hylton of Floyd Co, Va., from S.P. Weddle..
  - Poem written by Barbara Hylton, for Lorenzo Dow Hylton.
  - Two needlepoint samples, done by Barbara Hylton.
    Needlepoint 1
    Needlepoint 2
  - Letter from L.D. Hylton in "Indian Valley" to his cousin S. Weddle.
    Transcription Page 1 Page 2
  - Note written by James H. Guthrie.
  - Genealogical information about Lorenzo Hylton and his descendants, compiled by Robert Howell.